DOCTOR CHA
차 박사
ALL CHARACTERS, ORGANIZATIONS, EVENTS, AND LOCATIONS IN THIS SHOW ARE FICTITIOUS
모든 캐릭터, 조직, 이벤트, 이 쇼의 위치는 허구입니다.
Dr. Cha, were you a housewife while you weren't working?
차 박사님, 주부였나요? 일하지 않는 동안?
Yes.
예.
Your family must be well-off.
가족이 잘살아야 합니다.
What does your husband do?
남편은 무슨 일을 하나요?
My husband?
내 남편?
Your husband.
당신의 남편.
He's dead.
그는 죽었어.
-Ow! -Jung-min!
-아야! -정민!
-It's just alcohol. It's fine. -I'm okay.
- 그냥 술이에요. 괜찮습니다. - 난 괜찮아요.
It's okay.
괜찮아요.
Sorry.
죄송합니다.
Stop it.
그만해요.
-You're unbelievable. -Give me some tissues.
- 정말 말도 안 돼요. - 티슈 좀 주세요.
Dr. Cha.
차 박사.
I sincerely apologize.
진심으로 사과드립니다.
For what?
무엇을 위해?
I shouldn't have asked you that.
내가 너한테 그런 걸 물어보지 말았어야 했는데.
It's okay.
괜찮아요.
But if I may, may I ask you another rude question?
하지만 내가 할 수 있다면, 또 무례한 질문 하나 더 해도 될까요?
When did he pass away?
그는 언제 세상을 떠났습니까?
Well…
잘…
He's been dead for a long time.
그는 죽은 지 오래되었습니다.
Then may I ask you my final rude question?
그럼 마지막으로 무례한 질문 하나 드려도 될까요?
Do you miss him from time to time?
가끔 그 사람이 그리워요?
I can't remember.
기억이 나지 않습니다.
I can't even remember if I ever got married at all.
기억도 안나는데 내가 결혼이라도 했다면.
Let's wrap it up here.
여기서 마무리하겠습니다.
Drink up your beers!
맥주를 마셔보세요!
About things that will never come back
다시는 돌아오지 않을 것들에 대해
Next up is the new doctor Hollywood actors would be jealous of.
다음은 새로운 의사입니다 헐리우드 배우들이 부러워할 것 같아요.
Let's invite Professor Roy to the stage.
로이 교수님을 무대로 모시겠습니다.
Come on out!
나오세요!
I will kiss your eyes
나는 당신의 눈에 키스할 것이다
As thoughts race through your mind
생각이 마음속을 맴돌면서
Let's walk together
함께 걷자
After I met you
당신을 만난 후
You can pick who'll go next.
다음에 갈 사람을 선택할 수 있습니다.
Then I'll pick…
그럼 내가 고를게…
Dr. Cha Jeong-suk.
차정숙 박사님.
Me? No.
나? 아니요.
No. Come on.
아뇨. 어서요.
I can't sing.
나는 노래를 할 수 없습니다.
-Cha Jeong-suk!
-차정숙!
-It's okay.
-괜찮아요.
You only live once so make no regrets
인생은 한 번뿐이니 후회하지 마세요
Chase after what you truly want
당신이 진정으로 원하는 것을 쫓아라
Let's ride a flying magic carpet
날아다니는 마법의 양탄자를 타자
Over the magnificent blue sky
탁 트인 푸른 하늘 위에
Let's ride a red car
빨간 차를 타자
Across the magnificent emerald ocean
웅장한 에메랄드빛 바다를 건너
-Let's ride a flying magic carpet
-날아다니는 마법 양탄자를 타자 -날아다니는 마법의 양탄자를 타자
-Over the magnificent blue sky
-웅장하고 푸른 하늘 위로
-Let's enjoy this magnificent life
-이 멋진 삶을 즐기자
-You and I, us together
-너와 나, 우리가 함께 -너와 나, 우리는 함께
Goodbye, everyone.
안녕히 계세요, 여러분.
-Goodbye.
-안녕히 가세요.
Let me say one thing.
한 가지만 말씀드리겠습니다.
Today's group dinner is truly over.
오늘 단체식사가 정말 끝났습니다.
FEEL KARAOKE
노래방을 느껴보세요
Goodbye.
안녕.
-Goodbye.
-안녕히 가세요.
Professor.
교수.
-The designated driver will be here soon. -Okay.
-지정 운전기사가 곧 도착할 예정입니다. -좋아요.
Excuse me.
실례합니다.
How are you all going home?
다들 집에 어떻게 가시나요?
I'm planning to stay at the resident dorms.
나는 머물 계획이다 기숙사에서.
What about you?
당신은 어때요?
I'm…
나는…
going to take a taxi.
택시를 타러 갑니다.
Then I'll get going first.
그럼 나 먼저 가볼게.
Professor!
교수!
Which way are you going?
어느 쪽으로 가시나요?
Could you give me a ride?
저 좀 태워 주실 수 있나요?
Would you like that?
그렇게 하시겠습니까?
-Hop on. -Really?
-타세요. -정말?
Thank you.
감사합니다.
-I didn't drink, so no worries. -Okay.
- 술은 안 마셨으니 걱정하지 마세요. -좋아요.
-I'll go now. Hang tight.
-이제 갈게요. 꽉 잡아.
How is it?
어때요?
I love it.
나는 그것을 좋아한다.
But I don't like your choice of music.
하지만 나는 당신이 선택한 음악이 마음에 들지 않습니다.
Dr. Kim.
김 박사.
I feel nauseous.
메스꺼움을 느낀다.
How dare you?
어떻게 감히?
How dare I?
내가 어떻게 감히?
You may be my senior at the hospital but not here.
당신이 내 선배일 수도 있어요 병원에는 있지만 여기는 아니야.
Stay right there.
거기 그대로 있어.
Dr. Cha, do you feel better?
차박사님, 좀 나아지셨나요?
-Yes. -Have some water.
-예. - 물 좀 드세요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
I can't believe I'm here
내가 여기 있다는 걸 믿을 수 없어
at this hour.
이 시간에.
This isn't some place abroad.
이곳은 해외의 어떤 곳이 아닙니다.
Why couldn't you?
왜 할 수 없었나요?
Exactly.
정확히.
It wasn't as if I didn't have the money or the time.
안 그랬던 것 같진 않은데 돈이 있거나 시간이 있다.
So I wonder why.
그래서 왜인지 궁금합니다.
At least you're here now.
적어도 당신은 지금 여기에 있습니다.
How was the bike ride?
자전거 타기는 어땠나요?
It was the first time riding one in my life.
처음이었어요 내 인생에서 하나를 타고.
It was…
그것은…
truly amazing.
truly amazing.
It's hard to explain.
설명하기가 어렵습니다.
But it was incredible.
그러나 그것은 믿어지지 않았다.
You don't need to explain.
설명할 필요는 없습니다.
It feels great…
기분이 좋아…
to be alive.
살아 있기 위해.
It feels great that I can feel
느낄 수 있어서 너무 좋아요
freedom,
자유,
hunger,
배고픔,
and exhaustion.
그리고 피로.
I love it all.
나는 그것을 모두 좋아합니다.
So why does it feel like…
그럼 왜 그런 느낌이 드는 걸까요...
a burning rock is weighing down on my chest?
불타는 바위는 내 가슴을 짓눌러?
Dr. Kim.
김 박사.
Yes?
예?
Thank you for bearing with me
나와 함께 해주셔서 감사합니다
today.
오늘.
You don't need to thank me.
나한테 고마워할 필요는 없어.
Let's say I was building rapport.
내가 관계를 구축하고 있다고 가정 해 봅시다.
A bond between a doctor
의사 사이의 유대
and his patient.
그리고 그의 환자.
"Building rapport"?
"관계 구축"?
I like that.
나는 그것을 좋아한다.
But you know one too many humiliating things about me
하지만 당신은 하나를 너무 많이 알고 있습니다 나에 관한 굴욕적인 것들
for us to have rapport.
우리가 교감을 갖기 위해서요.
You must think I'm frustrating, right?
내가 답답하다고 생각하겠지?
I can't deny that.
나는 그것을 부인할 수 없습니다.
Why do you continue to live with him?
왜 계속 그 사람과 함께 살고 있습니까?
From what I see,
내가 보기에,
you seem like a great person to be around.
당신은 옆에 있으면 정말 좋은 사람인 것 같아요.
Is that so?
그렇습니까?
But you know what?
하지만 그거 알아요?
There are worse husbands than mine.
나보다 더 나쁜 남편도 있어요.
He wasn't always that cold.
그 사람이 항상 그렇게 차갑던 건 아니었어요.
It's just that…
그것은 단지 ...
we've been living together for a while now.
우리는 함께 살고 있어요 지금은 잠시 동안.
His love for me became weaker,
나를 향한 그의 사랑은 점점 약해졌고,
and he's become less grateful now.
이제 그는 감사하는 마음이 덜해졌습니다.
It's just like that.
정말 그렇습니다.
That's just how life is.
인생이 바로 그런 것입니다.
A married couple can't love each other passionately forever.
부부는 그럴 수 없다. 영원히 열정적으로 서로 사랑하십시오.
Even if that's the case,
그런 경우에도,
he should at least respect you.
그 사람은 적어도 당신을 존경해야 해요.
I was out of line.
나는 줄을 섰습니다.
Should we go?
우리 갈까?
We have work tomorrow.
우리는 내일 일이 있습니다.
What does your husband do?
남편은 무슨 일을 하나요?
My husband? He's dead.
내 남편? 그는 죽었어.
He's dead.
그는 죽었어.
Professor!
교수!
Which way are you going?
어느 쪽으로 가시나요?
Could you give me a ride?
저 좀 태워 주실 수 있나요?
She must be out of her mind.
그녀는 정신이 나갔나 보다.
She must be.
그녀는 분명합니다.
TO MY DAUGHTER
내 딸에게
I-rang.
아이링.
You must be surprised to find this letter.
당신은 이 편지를 발견하고 깜짝 놀랐을 것입니다.
I'm sure you're having a tough time
분명 힘든 시간을 보내고 있을 거야
because I'm so busy nowadays.
왜냐면 요즘 너무 바쁘거든요.
But if you think about it,
하지만 생각해 보면,
you'll have to experience this eventually
당신은 결국 이것을 경험해야 할 것입니다
since there will come a day when I won't be around anymore.
언젠가는 오겠죠 내가 더 이상 곁에 없을 때.
That is exactly why
그렇기 때문에 바로
I'd like to live for myself just once.
한번만이라도 나 자신을 위해 살고 싶다.
But that won't change the fact that I'll always be your mom.
하지만 그렇다고 사실이 바뀌지는 않습니다 내가 항상 너희 엄마일 거라고.
Just like how I always root for you and your dreams,
이와 마찬가지로 나는 항상 당신과 당신의 꿈을 응원합니다.
just this once,
이번 한 번만,
I hope you can do the same for me too.
당신도 나에게 똑같이 할 수 있기를 바랍니다.
What I need the most right now
지금 나에게 가장 필요한 것은
is your encouragement and support.
여러분의 격려와 지지입니다.
I love you, my daughter.
사랑해요, 내 딸.
From Mom.
엄마에게서.
-Jung-min. -Good morning.
-정민. -좋은 아침이에요.
Eat this before the others come.
다른 사람들이 오기 전에 이것을 먹어라.
-What is it? -Here.
-이게 뭐죠? -여기.
It's
그것은
It looks good. What about you?
좋아 보인다. 당신은 어때요?
I'm okay.
난 괜찮아.
Thanks, Mom.
고마워요, 엄마.
It's so good.
너무 좋아요.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
You're having
당신은
Carbs are the best hangover food.
탄수화물은 최고의 숙취 음식이다.
Where did you get it?
어디서 구했어요?
I bought it.
나는 그것을 샀다.
Really?
정말?
I can have some, right? Thanks.
좀 먹어도 돼요, 그렇죠? 감사해요.
This is really good.
정말 좋습니다.
Would you like some too?
당신도 좀 드시겠어요?
Did you already eat?
벌써 식사하셨나요?
That's Dr. Seo's.
그게 서 박사님의 거예요.
What do you mean? We share everything here.
무슨 뜻이에요? 우리는 여기서 모든 것을 공유합니다.
-Right? -Sorry? Yes.
-오른쪽? -죄송합니다? 예.
Dr. Seo.
서 박사.
You should eat.
먹어야 해.
Or she'll eat it all.
아니면 그 사람이 다 먹을 거예요.
This is good.
이것은 좋다.
Where did you buy this?
이거 어디서 샀어요?
-Stop it. -You know what?
-그만해요. - 그거 알아요?
It's good, but the rice is too mushy.
좋은데 밥이 너무 질겨요.
-It's too mushy? -Yes.
-너무 퍽퍽해요? -예.
-Ma'am. -Yes?
-부인. -예?
Look.
보세요.
-It's about how you clean the bathroom. -Okay.
-화장실 청소 방법에 관한 것입니다. -좋아요.
I know it's more convenient to use a lot of products,
그게 더 편한걸로 알아요 많은 제품을 사용하고,
but that leaves behind a strong smell.
하지만 그러면 강한 냄새가 남습니다.
Then what should I use instead?
그러면 대신 무엇을 사용해야 합니까?
My daughter-in-law used stale cola
며느리가 상한 콜라를 마셨어요
or old shampoo.
아니면 오래된 샴푸.
-Okay. -One more thing.
-좋아요. -한 가지 더.
The ratio of the ingredients for the detox juice is important.
성분의 비율 해독 주스가 중요합니다.
You added too little fruit
과일을 너무 적게 넣었어요
and it tastes too tart.
그리고 맛이 너무 시큼해요.
I made it exactly as you told me to.
알려주신대로 정확하게 만들었어요.
Then I guess you're just not good at making food.
그럼 내 생각엔 당신은 음식을 만드는 데 능숙하지 않습니다.
How did you make the juice before?
이전에는 주스를 어떻게 만들었나요?
My daughter-in-law made them taste great even with the same recipe.
며느리가 맛있게 만들어줬어요 같은 레시피인데도 말이죠.
She must've slaved away.
그녀는 노예가 된 게 틀림없어요.
Look.
바라보다.
I can't do this anymore.
나는 더 이상 이것을 할 수 없습니다.
Just ask your daughter-in-law to do it for you.
며느리한테 한번 물어보세요 당신을 위해 그것을하기 위해.
You'll never find a helper
넌 절대 도우미를 찾을 수 없을 거야
who'll suit your taste.
누가 네 취향에 맞을지.
Goodness.
선량.
Jeez.
이런.
Wait.
기다리다.
Ma'am.
부인.
We have the prescription ready for Ms. Jung Seong-a in Room 810
처방전이 준비되어 있어요 810호 정성아씨에게
and I've checked the results.
그리고 결과를 확인해 봤습니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
Hello, ma'am.
안녕하세요, 부인.
I can't work for your family anymore.
나는 더 이상 당신 가족을 위해 일할 수 없습니다.
She nitpicks every single thing,
그녀는 모든 것을 따져보고,
and it stresses me out so much.
그리고 그것은 나에게 너무 많은 스트레스를 준다.
I'm quitting today,
오늘 퇴사합니다,
-so that's that. -Ma'am, but--
-그렇군요. -부인, 하지만--
What on earth--
도대체 무슨 일이--
How could you prescribe eight ampoules of digoxin?
어떻게 처방할 수 있었나요? 디곡신 8앰플?
Did you want the patient to die?
환자가 죽기를 바라셨나요?
I understand maybe you were too ignorant to notice,
이해해요 어쩌면 넌 너무 무지해서 눈치채지 못했어
but didn't it seem weird to prescribe eight ampoules?
근데 좀 이상한 것 같지 않았어? 앰플 8개 처방하려고?
The Cardiology Department said to prescribe 2mg of digoxin so…
심장학과 디곡신 2mg을 처방한다고 해서..
They told you to give 2mg in an IV drip?
IV 드립에 2mg을 주라고 했나요?
Don't you mean "two ampoules"?
"앰플 2개"라는 뜻이 아닌가요?
Are you so clueless you can't tell what's fine and what isn't?
너무 무식해서 말을 못하냐 괜찮은 것은 무엇이고 그렇지 않은 것은 무엇입니까?
-Thankfully, I spotted it beforehand. -I got a call.
-다행히 미리 알아냈어요. -전화가 왔습니다.
Do you know what would've happened if you administered that much?
무슨 일이 일어났을지 아시나요? 그렇게 많이 투여했다면?
You're forbidden from prescribing on your own without asking someone first.
처방을 금지하고 있습니다. 누구에게도 먼저 묻지 않고 스스로.
Make sure to ask before making proper prescriptions.
꼭 물어보세요 제대로 된 처방을 내리기 전에
Understood?
이해했다?
Yes, ma'am.
네, 부인.
I'll ask before I make a prescription.
처방전에 물어보겠습니다.
Don't be so harsh on a first-year resident.
너무 가혹하게 말하지 마세요 1년차 레지던트에요.
She's still recovering. Don't you feel bad?
그녀는 아직 회복 중입니다. 기분 나쁘지 않나요?
Then she shouldn't have come here.
그렇다면 그녀는 여기에 오지 말았어야 했습니다.
It's better for her to quit than to inconvenience others.
그 사람은 그만 두는 게 나을 것 같아 다른 사람에게 불편을 끼치는 것보다
Hold on.
기다리다.
She patted your bottom last time, right?
저번에 그 사람이 네 엉덩이를 두들겼지, 그렇지?
Isn't that sexual harassment?
그거 성희롱 아닌가요?
I should report her to the disciplinary committee.
그 사람을 신고해야겠어 징계위원회에.
She just did that because I was like a son to her.
그 사람이 방금 그랬어 왜냐하면 나는 그 사람에게 아들과 같았기 때문입니다.
Don't be ridiculous.
말도 안되는 소리하지 마십시오.
Hey.
여기요.
That's one of the excuses
그게 변명 중 하나야
old men use after sexually harassing young girls.
노인들이 사용하는 어린 소녀들을 성희롱한 후.
Don't be ludicrous.
말도 안되는 소리하지 마십시오.
I get it.
알겠습니다.
At least talk nicely.
적어도 친절하게 말해보세요.
Imagine what she'll think of you.
그녀가 당신에 대해 어떻게 생각할지 상상해보세요.
Who cares--
누가 신경쓰겠어--
Look at you.
당신을보세요.
You never talked back to me.
당신은 나에게 다시 말을 한 적이 없습니다.
I mean, it'll taint our department's reputation.
내 말은, 오염될 거라는 거야 우리 부서의 평판.
And I don't like seeing you
그리고 난 당신을 보는 걸 좋아하지 않아요
acting so cold toward someone who's old enough to be your mother.
누군가에게 너무 차갑게 대하는 것 당신의 어머니가 될 만큼 나이가 많은 사람이요.
Then she should do better.
그러면 그녀는 더 잘해야 합니다.
Then I'll be nice.
그럼 내가 친절하게 대할게.
And if she doesn't?
그리고 그녀가 그렇지 않다면?
Then I'll be ruthless.
그러면 나는 무자비해질 것이다.
No one is good from the start.
처음부터 좋은 사람은 없습니다.
I was.
나는 그랬다.
Mom.
엄마.
Don't be too upset.
너무 화내지 마세요.
She never shows mercy to anyone.
그녀는 누구에게도 자비를 베풀지 않습니다.
I get it.
알겠습니다.
I deserved to be scolded for my mistake.
나는 내 실수로 인해 꾸중을 받아 마땅했습니다.
I understand why she was mad.
나는 그녀가 왜 화가 났는지 이해합니다.
I get that she's merciless, but still.
나는 그녀가 무자비하다는 것을 알고 있지만 여전히.
How could she be so harsh to someone who's old enough to be her mother?
그녀는 어떻게 누군가에게 그렇게 가혹할 수 있는가? 그녀의 어머니가 될 만큼 나이가 많은 사람은 누구입니까?
She called me ignorant. My goodness.
그녀는 나를 무지하다고 불렀습니다. 이럴 수가.
Jeez.
이런.
With that personality of hers, she'll never become a great doctor.
그녀의 그런 성격으로, 그 사람은 결코 훌륭한 의사가 될 수 없을 거예요.
Don't get too close to her.
그녀에게 너무 가까이 다가가지 마세요.
Even though I'm sure you won't.
나는 당신이 그렇게하지 않을 것이라고 확신하지만.
Right.
오른쪽.
How dare she eat all your
그녀가 어떻게 감히 너의 모든 것을 먹어치울 수 있겠는가?
Jung-min, my neck is killing me.
정민아 목이 아프다
Can you massage it?
마사지해 주실 수 있나요?
Where?
어디?
-Where? -Your grandmother is just…
-어디? -할머니는 그냥...
It hurts. Here.
아파요. 여기.
-Here? -Yes.
-여기? -예.
Don't feel too hurt.
너무 상처받지 마세요.
Will this raise the area around my eyes too much?
이게 올라갈까 내 눈 주위가 너무 많은가?
I'm skilled at what I do, ma'am.
저는 제가 하는 일에 능숙해요, 부인.
I'll only add a bit, so it'll be fine.
조금만 추가하면 괜찮을 것 같아요.
I'll put some between your eyebrows too.
눈썹 사이에도 좀 넣어줄게요.
Okay.
좋아요.
-Goodness.
-선량.
Hello, Ms. Oh.
안녕하세요, 오씨.
Goodness, hello.
맙소사, 안녕하세요.
What brings you here?
무슨 일로 여기까지 왔나요?
Hello, ma'am.
안녕하세요, 부인.
Hey, it's been a while.
안녕하세요, 오랜만이에요.
I'm a regular here.
나는 여기 단골이다.
I see.
알겠어요.
I guess you're here for some botox.
보톡스를 맞으러 오셨나 봐요.
I thought you preferred maintaining your natural beauty.
나는 당신이 선호한다고 생각했습니다 자연스러운 아름다움을 유지하세요.
I guess you had a change of heart.
마음이 바뀌셨나 봅니다.
Goodness.
선량.
I guess you didn't hear.
아마 당신이 듣지 못한 것 같아요.
Jung-min, my eldest grandson,
큰손자 정민이
said he'd pay for botox shots as my birthday gift.
보톡스 주사 비용을 지불하겠다고 말했어 내 생일 선물로.
I refused out of embarrassment,
부끄러워서 거절했는데,
but I had no choice because he had already made a reservation.
하지만 나에겐 선택의 여지가 없었다 왜냐하면 그는 이미 예약을 했기 때문이다.
Right.
오른쪽.
Jung-min is quite considerate.
정민이는 배려심이 많아요.
I'll leave you to it then.
그럼 그 일에 맡기겠습니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
-See you later, ma'am. - Okay.
- 나중에 뵙겠습니다, 부인. - 좋아요.
Hey.
여기요.
How could you book me around the same time as her?
어떻게 예약할 수 있어요? 그 사람이랑 거의 같은 시기에?
The nurses don't know that you're in-laws.
간호사들은 당신이 시댁 식구인지도 모릅니다.
This is unbelievable.
이것은 믿을 수 없습니다.
Ms. Oh, that was some quick thinking.
아, 정말 빠른 생각이군요.
How did you instantly come up with such a lie?
어떻게 즉시 했나요? 그런 거짓말을 생각해?
Jeong-suk is smart all thanks to me.
정숙이는 나 덕분에 똑똑해졌어.
By the way,
그건 그렇고,
Mi-hee.
미희.
I want to ask you something.
나는 당신에게 뭔가를 물어보고 싶습니다.
Jung-min, that brat.
정민아, 그 새끼야.
All he did on my birthday was pass me the money Jeong-suk had given him.
내 생일에 그 사람이 한 일은 나를 지나친 것 뿐이었어 정숙이 준 돈.
It's true they're never grateful for your babysitting.
사실 그들은 결코 감사하지 않습니다 당신의 육아를 위해.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
-Hello. -I'll be treating you today.
-안녕하세요. -오늘은 내가 진료할게.
Okay.
좋아요.
It does look suspicious.
의심스러워 보입니다.
I only knew about it after someone at the bathhouse pointed it out.
누군가가 나서서야 알았어 목욕탕에서 그것을 지적했다.
It neither looked like an age spot nor a mole.
둘 다 닮지 않았어 검버섯이나 점.
I was worried, so I came here.
걱정이 되어 여기까지 왔습니다.
Ms. Oh.
오 씨.
I'll write you a referral
추천글 써드릴께요
so you should go and get a biopsy done at a hospital.
그러니 너는 가야 해 그리고 병원에서 생체검사를 받으세요.
What's wrong?
무슨 일이야?
Do you think it's skin cancer?
피부암인 것 같나요?
Of course not.
물론 그렇지 않습니다.
That's very unlikely.
그럴 가능성은 거의 없습니다.
But it's always better to be sure and check just in case.
하지만 항상 확신하는 것이 더 좋습니다 만약을 대비해 확인해 보세요.
Right.
오른쪽.
Keep this a secret from Jeong-suk.
정숙에게는 비밀로 해주세요.
She already has a lot on her plate.
그녀는 이미 접시에 많은 것을 가지고 있습니다.
Yes, ma'am.
네, 부인.
But promise me you'll get that checked out.
하지만 약속해 당신은 그것을 확인하게 될 것입니다.
Jeez.
이런.
Why is she saying I should go to a hospital?
그녀가 말하는 이유는 무엇입니까? 병원에 가야 하나요?
-You're a bit late. -Yes, I am.
- 좀 늦었군요. -네, 그렇습니다.
Please get in.
들어가주세요.
What's going on between those two?
그 둘 사이에 무슨 일이 벌어지고 있는 걸까요?
Are they dating?
데이트 중인가요?
What's all this?
이게 다 뭐야?
It's a small token of my gratitude for the amazing ride last night.
작은 감사의 표시예요 어젯밤의 놀라운 라이딩을 위해.
It's nothing. I was just going to put it here and leave.
그것은 아무것도 아니다. 난 그냥 가려고 했어 여기에 두고 떠나려고요.
We should share this.
우리는 이것을 공유해야 합니다.
How about we go and eat this at the cafeteria?
우리 가는 게 어때? 이걸 구내식당에서 먹나요?
I could eat right now.
지금 당장 먹을 수 있었어요.
I just need to remove the catheter from one of the patients.
카테터만 제거하면 돼요 환자 중 한 명에게서.
-I'll meet you there. -Okay.
-거기서 만나요. -좋아요.
Your food is safe.
당신의 음식은 안전합니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
He's the new chief of the Hepatobiliary and Pancreas Department.
그는 간담도의 새로운 책임자입니다 췌장과.
-Is that so? -Yes.
-그렇습니까? -예.
I thought he was a celebrity at first.
처음엔 연예인인 줄 알았어요.
He's from the US.
그는 미국 출신이에요.
I heard he's single.
그 사람이 싱글이라고 들었거든요.
He may be single, but I bet he's doing plenty of mingling.
그 사람은 싱글일 수도 있고, 하지만 그 사람은 많이 어울리고 있는 것 같아요.
Exactly.
정확히.
-I'm sorry for being late. -That's okay.
-늦어서 죄송해요. - 괜찮아요.
It looks delicious.
맛있어 보이네요.
I can't guarantee the taste.
맛은 보장 못해요.
I'm sure it'll be good.
나는 그것이 좋을 것이라고 확신한다.
Let me open that for you.
제가 직접 열어보겠습니다.
-I added vegetables so it'll be healthier. -Is that so?
- 야채를 추가해서 더 건강하게 먹었어요. -그렇습니까?
Please enjoy your food.
맛있게 드시기 바랍니다.
Professor?
교수?
I've been feeling unwell today.
오늘 몸이 안 좋아졌어요.
You can eat without me.
나 없이도 먹을 수 있어요.
What the heck am I doing right now?
나는 지금 도대체 뭘 하고 있는 걸까?
It'll be quick.
빨리 될 거예요.
Gosh.
이런.
One minute.
1분.
You can wrap it up from here.
여기서 마무리하시면 됩니다.
-Hello? -Hey, Jung-min.
-안녕하세요? -안녕하세요, 정민 씨.
Can you help me remove the PCD?
PCD 제거를 도와주실 수 있나요?
Can I just take it out?
그냥 꺼내도 될까요?
-Good work. -Thank you.
- 잘했어요. -감사합니다.
-Hey, Mom. -Jung-min.
-안녕하세요, 엄마. -정민.
Can you help me insert the central line?
중심선 삽입을 도와주실 수 있나요?
I've never done it before.
나는 전에 그것을 한 적이 없습니다.
Hello?
안녕하세요?
How do I explain the surgery?
수술을 어떻게 설명하나요?
It's a LAR. What was it again?
LAR입니다. 또 뭐였지?
Hello?
안녕하세요?
The doctor told me to insert a silastic drain into the wound.
의사가 삽입하라고 하더군요 상처로의 실라스틱 배수.
How do I do it?
어떻게 해야 하나요?
Hello?
안녕하세요?
-Hello? -Jung-min.
-안녕하세요? -정민.
Jung-min. I can't remember.
정민. 기억이 나지 않습니다.
Tell me. Come here quickly.
말해 주세요. 빨리 여기로 오세요.
-Hello? -Gosh.
-안녕하세요? -맙소사.
And you call yourself a doctor?
그런데 당신은 스스로를 의사라고 부르나요?
Why aren't you sending her to the operating room?
왜 그녀를 보내지 않는거야? 수술실로?
-Sir. -The patient needs surgery now!
-선생님. -환자는 지금 수술이 필요합니다!
-Look-- -When are you going to operate?
-보세요-- - 언제 수술할 거예요?
Gosh, my neck.
이런, 내 목.
Hi, Jung-min.
안녕하세요, 정민님.
Enough is enough. You've really crossed the line.
충분합니다. 당신은 정말로 선을 넘었습니다.
What?
무엇?
I thought you were smart back in med school.
난 당신이 똑똑하다고 생각했어요 다시 의과대학으로.
You scored 49 points on the resident exams.
49점을 획득하셨습니다. 레지던트 시험에
So how do you not know anything?
그럼 어떻게 아무것도 모르나요?
Come on. I had a long break in between.
어서 해봐요. 그 사이에 긴 휴식 시간을 가졌습니다.
If you had a long break,
오랫동안 쉬었다면,
you should've studied by watching online videos in the meantime.
넌 공부했어야 했는데 그 동안 온라인 비디오를 보면서.
I'm always scolded for not knowing any better.
나는 항상 꾸중을 듣는다 더 나은 것을 모르기 때문에.
I don't need you bothering me too.
당신도 나를 귀찮게 할 필요가 없습니다.
Why did you have to come to our department?
왜 그랬어? 우리 부서로 오려고?
Hey!
여기요!
I can't believe you.
나는 당신을 믿을 수 없습니다.
I carried you in my womb for ten months
나는 열 달 동안 너를 내 자궁 속에 품고 있었어
and put my life on the line to give birth to you.
그리고 내 목숨을 걸고 당신을 낳기 위해.
I cleaned after you.
나는 당신을 따라 청소했습니다.
I taught you how to talk and count, and raised you until now.
나는 너에게 말하는 법과 계산하는 법을 가르쳤고, 그리고 지금까지 당신을 키워왔습니다.
So how dare you complain and look down on me
그러니 어떻게 감히 불평을 합니까? 그리고 나를 내려다봐
just because I asked you for some help?
내가 너한테 도움을 청했기 때문에?
How could you?
어떻게 그럴 수 있니?
Look, Mom.
보세요, 엄마.
That's not what I meant. I was--
내 말은 그런 뜻이 아니었어. 나는--
"Mom"?
"엄마"?
I thought you wanted to keep that a secret?
난 당신이 원하는 줄 알았는데 그걸 비밀로 하려고?
You can take my night duty tonight, you jerk.
당신은 걸릴 수 있습니다 오늘 밤 내 야간 근무야, 이 멍청아.
I'm already on night duty tonight.
나는 오늘 밤에 이미 야간 근무 중입니다.
I don't want to hear it!
나는 그것을 듣고 싶지 않다!
Darn it.
젠장.
Mom.
엄마.
That wasn't what I meant.
내 말은 그런 뜻이 아니었어.
MY SON
내 아들
MOM, CHECK OUT THIS VIDEO
엄마, 이 영상을 보세요
TIP 2. POSITIVE PRESSURE I WILL DEMONSTRATE WITH A DISTAL LUMEN
팁 2. 양압 나는 DISTAL LUMEN으로 시연하겠습니다.
My gosh.
맙소사.
TO SHOW YOU HOW YOUR BLOOD PRESSURE WORKS
방법을 보여주기 위해 혈압은 효과가 있습니다
This is a whole new world.
이것은 완전히 새로운 세계입니다.
He should've sent this to me sooner.
그 사람이 나한테 이걸 좀 더 빨리 보냈어야 했는데.
A 68-year-old female patient.
68세 여성 환자입니다.
The primary cancer is in her ascending colon,
원발성 암 그녀의 상행 결장에 있습니다.
and it's quite large.
그리고 꽤 크네요.
The cancer cells have metastasized to her liver as well.
암세포가 전이됐어요 그녀의 간에도 마찬가지다.
The lung CT scan shows that they've metastasized
폐 CT 스캔 결과는 다음과 같습니다. 그들은 전이됐어
to two areas on the right lung and one area on the left lung.
오른쪽 폐의 두 부위로 왼쪽 폐의 한 부분.
They've also metastasized to her spine, so surgery won't be an option.
척추에도 전이됐고 그래서 수술은 선택 사항이 아닙니다.
She should receive chemotherapy as soon as possible.
그녀는 화학요법을 받아야 한다 가능한 한 빨리.
-Chief Resident Hwang. -Yes, sir.
- 황 소장. - 네, 선생님.
Contact the Oncology Department for a consultation.
종양학과에 문의하세요 상담을 위해.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
-But what crime did she commit? -Murder, sir.
-그런데 그 사람은 무슨 죄를 지었나요? - 살인입니다.
She received a life sentence for poisoning her husband.
그녀는 종신형을 선고받았습니다 남편을 독살한 죄로.
Who's in charge of her?
그녀를 담당하는 사람은 누구입니까?
It's me, sir.
저예요.
I heard she's refusing treatment. Can you persuade her?
치료를 거부한다고 들었습니다. 그녀를 설득할 수 있나요?
I'll do my best.
최선을 다하겠습니다.
That's a given.
그것은 주어진 것입니다.
What's important is the result.
중요한 것은 결과입니다.
Ma'am.
부인.
Your will to live matters the most when it comes to receiving treatment.
살고자 하는 의지가 가장 중요하다 치료를 받을 때.
If you continue to refuse treatment,
계속해서 치료를 거부하는 경우,
the pain will gradually worsen.
통증은 점차 심해질 것이다.
And you won't be able to live as long.
그리고 당신은 오래 살 수 없을 것입니다.
I understand that you feel hopeless.
나는 당신이 절망감을 느낀다는 것을 이해합니다.
But there have been patients who survived even worse conditions
그런데 환자가 있었어요 더 나쁜 상황에서도 살아남은 사람
and lived for years.
그리고 수년간 살았습니다.
This is the VIP ward. The patient is very agitated.
이곳은 VIP 병동입니다. 환자는 매우 불안해합니다.
-Call the director! -Please hurry.
-감독님한테 전화해! - 서둘러 주세요.
What is this?
이게 뭔가요?
-Jeez! -It's a complete mess here.
- 이런! - 여기는 완전 엉망이에요.
Can you still not reach them?
아직도 연락이 안 되나요?
-No, I can't. -Darn it!
-아니요, 그럴 수 없어요. -젠장!
Darn it!
젠장!
Yes, I'm glad you're here.
네, 당신이 여기 있어서 기뻐요.
I should've known how lousy this hospital was
난 알았어야 했는데 이 병원이 얼마나 형편없었는지
the moment they sent this rookie resident over.
보낸 순간 이 신인 거주자는 끝났습니다.
One of your professors told me something ludicrous today.
교수님 중 한 분 오늘 나한테 이상한 말을 했어.
A colostomy?
결장루?
I was told I'll have to live with a bag attached to me from now on.
살아야 한다고 하더군요 지금부터 나에게 가방을 달고.
That's correct. We'll have to do the surgery to be sure,
맞습니다. 확실히 수술을 해봐야 알겠지만,
-but it's highly likely that-- -Darn it!
-하지만 그럴 가능성이 매우 높습니다-- -젠장!
Are you telling me to carry around a poop bag?
나한테 말하는 거야? 똥주머니 들고 다니려고?
Do you have any idea how much money I've spent on this hospital?
돈이 얼마나 되는지 아시나요? 내가 이 병원에 돈을 썼다고?
How dare you say that?
어떻게 감히 그런 말을 할 수 있나요?
Get out!
나가세요!
Bring me the director of this hospital this instant!
이 병원 원장을 데려오세요 이 순간!
Please calm down--
진정하세요--
Shut up! How dare you order me around?
닥쳐! 감히 나에게 명령을 내리다니?
Bring me the director this instant!
당장 감독님을 데려오세요!
Sir.
선생님.
This isn't an issue you can solve by calling the director over.
이건 네가 해결할 수 있는 문제가 아니야 감독님한테 전화해서.
You can't--
당신은 할 수 없습니다 -
Darn it.
젠장.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
PATIENT: OH CHANG-GYU
환자 : 오창규
This is Cha Jeong-suk.
차정숙입니다.
Me?
나?
I've never done it before, but…
한 번도 해본 적이 없지만...
Okay. I'll do it.
알았어. 내가 할게요.
Please bring me the portable X-ray.
휴대용 엑스레이를 가져다 주세요.
Yes, ma'am.
네, 부인.
Hello, Doctor.
안녕하세요, 박사님.
I'm Dr. Cha Jeong-suk who's on night duty.
야간 당직 박사 차정숙 입니다.
I inserted a C-line,
C라인을 삽입했는데,
and the X-ray shows a pneumothorax.
엑스레이에는 기흉이 보입니다.
I think we need to insert a chest tube,
흉관을 삽입해야 할 것 같은데,
but I have no experience with it yet.
하지만 나는 아직 그것에 대한 경험이 없습니다.
DOCTOR IM SEON-U
임선우 박사
Hello, is this Dr. Im Seon-u of the CS Department?
안녕하세요 임선우박사님이신가요? CS부서?
I see. You're doing emergency surgery.
알겠어요. You're doing emergency surgery.
Darn it.
젠장.
-Sir, are you a second-year resident? -Yes.
- 선생님, 레지던트 2년차이신가요? -예.
I inserted a C-line and took an X-ray.
C라인을 삽입하고 엑스레이를 찍었습니다.
I confirmed a pneumothorax.
기흉을 확인했습니다.
Could you insert a chest tube for me?
흉관을 삽입해 주실 수 있나요?
I'm sorry, but I don't have much experience with that yet.
죄송하지만 저는 없어요 아직은 경험이 많아요.
Why did you do it instead of asking someone more experienced to handle it?
묻지도 않고 왜 그랬어? 그것을 처리할 경험이 더 많은 사람이 있나요?
All of them were busy.
그들 모두는 바빴습니다.
No one from the CS Department is available.
CS 부서 직원 없음 사용할 수 있습니다.
What should I do?
어떻게 해야 하나요?
I--
나는--
JUNG-MIN'S MOM
정민의 엄마
What is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
I'm at the ER right now.
저는 지금 응급실에 있어요.
Can you come here?
여기로 올 수 있나요?
What happened?
무슨 일이에요?
I don't know how to insert a chest tube.
흉관 삽입 방법을 모르겠습니다.
Is that why you called me?
그래서 나한테 전화한 거야?
It's not even worth answering, so I'm hanging up.
대답할 가치도 없고, 그래서 끊을게.
You shamelessly lied that your husband is dead,
뻔뻔하게 거짓말을 했어 당신 남편이 죽었다고,
yet you want a favor?
그런데 부탁 좀 들어줄래?
You should call a more experienced resident for something like this.
경험이 많은 사람에게 전화하세요 이런 일을 위해 거주합니다.
I did, but no one--
그랬는데 아무도--
GUSAN UNIVERSITY HOSPITAL
구산대학교병원
RESIDENT CHA JEONG-SUK
차정숙 주민
Hello?
안녕하세요?
Dr. Jeon, this is Cha Jeong-suk. I need your help with something.
전 박사님, 차정석입니다. 뭔가 당신의 도움이 필요해요.
Don't you know I just clocked out?
내가 방금 퇴근한 거 모르세요?
I know. I'm really sorry.
알아요. 정말 죄송해요.
It's just that I don't know how to insert a chest tube.
그냥 모르겠어요 흉관 삽입 방법
Hold on.
잠깐만요.
I spotted a pneumothorax--
기흉을 발견했어요...
I'll be there, so wait!
내가 거기 있을 테니 기다려라!
Thank you.
감사합니다.
JUNG-MIN'S MOM
정민의 엄마
What is it now?
지금은 무엇입니까?
Honey.
꿀.
I mean, hello?
내 말은, 안녕?
-Hello? -What is it?
-안녕하세요? -이게 뭐죠?
I'm afraid you'll have to come.
당신이 와야 할 것 같아요.
The patient's condition is worsening.
환자의 상태가 악화되고 있습니다.
Are you insane?
미쳤어?
What would the others think if I showed up there
다른 사람들은 어떻게 생각할까? 내가 거기 나타났다면
just because you called?
단지 네가 전화했기 때문에?
Who cares about that when the patient can't breathe?
누가 그런 걸 신경쓰나요 환자가 숨을 쉴 수 없을 때?
If you don't come,
당신이 오지 않으면,
I will expose our relationship to everyone in the hospital.
우리 관계를 폭로할게 병원에 있는 모든 사람에게.
How ridiculous.
정말 우스꽝 스럽습니다.
What did you say?
뭐라고 하셨나요?
Dr. Seo, over here.
서 박사님, 여기요.
Hurry!
서두르다!
EMERGENCY MEDICAL CENTER
응급 의료 센터
Is it not working?
작동하지 않나요?
You can't do it?
당신은 그것을 할 수 없습니다?
-Why isn't it working? -Be quiet already!
-Why isn't it working? -벌써 조용히 해!
I don't know if it's in or not.
들어있는지 아닌지는 모르겠습니다.
It's about 3cm in, right?
3cm 정도 되는 것 같죠?
Why are you having trouble with this? You're a professor.
왜 이런 문제가 발생합니까? 당신은 교수입니다.
It's been ten years!
10년이 지났습니다!
I'm not someone who has time to do things like this.
나는 누군가가 아니다 이런 일을 할 시간이 있는 사람.
Dr. Jeon!
전 박사님!
Professor?
교수?
Why are you here?
당신은 왜 여기에 있습니까?
-Let me. -No.
-하자. -아니요.
I'm almost done.
이제 거의 끝났습니다.
All right.
괜찮은.
Let me see how good you are.
당신이 얼마나 좋은지 보자.
Wrap it up.
마무리하세요.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
Please prepare the suture.
봉합사를 준비해주세요.
-Connect the chest drainage bottle. -Yes, ma'am.
-흉부 배액병을 연결합니다. -네, 부인.
Sir.
선생님.
Can you hear me?
내 말 들려요?
Can you try to cough?
기침을 해볼 수 있나요?
Well done.
잘하셨어요.
Now that he's okay, I should get going.
이제 그 사람은 괜찮으니 가봐야겠어요.
Dress him well.
Dress him well.
I'll leave you to it.
나는 당신에게 맡기겠습니다.
Thank you, sir.
감사합니다.
My pleasure.
천만에요.
-Get the dressing ready. -Okay.
-드레싱을 준비하세요. -좋아요.
He came here because of that first-year resident.
그는 여기에 왔다 그 1년차 레지던트 때문에.
What's gotten into him?
그에게 무슨 일이 생겼나요?
When that resident was speaking to him on the phone,
그 주민이 있었을 때 그 사람이랑 전화로 얘기하고,
she said, "Honey."
그녀는 "여보"라고 말했습니다.
I heard them talking as I passed by, and they were talking casually.
지나가면서 얘기하는 걸 들었는데, 그리고 그들은 아무렇지도 않게 이야기를 나누었습니다.
But I heard she's a widow. Is something going on between them?
그런데 그 사람이 과부라고 들었어요. 그들 사이에 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는 걸까요?
Aren't you…
그렇지 않나요?
scared of me?
내가 무서워?
I'm sure you heard about what crime I committed.
분명 들었을 거야 내가 무슨 범죄를 저질렀는지.
Yes.
예.
I'm aware.
나는 알고 있다.
Then you should tend to other patients instead.
그럼 당신은 경향이 있어야 대신 다른 환자들에게
I want to stay here quietly
나는 여기에 조용히 머물고 싶다
and just vanish into thin air.
그리고 그냥 허공으로 사라집니다.
So use your valuable skills
그러니 당신의 소중한 기술을 활용하세요
on those who deserve to live.
살아갈 자격이 있는 사람들에게.
Yes. I'm sorry.
예. 죄송합니다.
We tried to dissuade him but…
우리는 그를 설득하려 했으나...
Okay. I'm sorry.
알았어. 죄송합니다.
Chairman Oh, I see you're having a late-night snack.
아 회장님, 그러시는 것 같군요. 야식.
Isn't it obvious?
분명하지 않나요?
I guess you've made up your mind, right?
결정하신 것 같은데요, 그렇죠?
Then when should we schedule your surgery?
그러면 수술 일정은 언제로 잡아야 할까요?
Surgery, my foot.
수술해라, 내 발.
Are you not going to get it?
안 받을 건가요?
Do you expect me to get it after what you guys told me?
내가 그것을 얻을 것이라고 기대합니까? 너희들이 나한테 말한 후에?
How dare you incompetent people tell me what to do?
무능한 사람들이 감히 어떻게 해야 할지 말해줘?
I'm going to rest here for a few days
나 여기서 며칠간 쉴 거야
then get treated at the biggest hospital in the US at all costs!
그럼 큰 병원에서 치료 받아 어떤 대가를 치르더라도 미국에서!
Chairman Oh.
오 회장.
Our hospital is among the world's best when it comes to this department.
우리 병원은 세계 최고 수준이다 이 부서에 오면.
There's no guarantee
보장은 없어요
that the hospitals there will give you better treatment.
거기 병원들 더 나은 치료를 해드리겠습니다.
I don't want to hear it, so leave.
듣기 싫으니 나가세요.
Raise the volume.
볼륨을 높이세요.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
Hello, Professor.
안녕하세요, 교수님.
-Hello. -You're still here.
-안녕하세요. - 아직 여기 계시군요.
I'm checking on my patients.
환자들을 확인하고 있어요.
Aren't you off work tomorrow?
내일 회사 안 쉬나요?
-Yes. -What do you have in mind?
-예. -무엇을 염두에 두고 있나요?
Spending time with my family.
가족과 함께 시간을 보냅니다.
I've been neglecting them these days.
나는 요즘 그들을 소홀히 하고 있다.
What will you be up to tomorrow?
내일 뭐 할 거야?
I'm going to look for someone.
나는 누군가를 찾으러 갈 것이다.
Who?
WHO?
Me.
나.
How's work?
일은 어때요?
Some of my patients refuse to receive treatment.
내 환자 중 일부는 거부합니다. 치료를 받기 위해.
They all have different reasons.
그들은 모두 다른 이유를 가지고 있습니다.
Even the most competent doctors won't be able to do anything in such a situation.
아무리 유능한 의사라도 그렇지는 않을 것이다. 그런 상황에서는 뭐든지 할 수 있다.
So I have absolutely no idea how to persuade them.
그래서 전혀 모르겠어요 그들을 설득하는 방법.
Others may not be able to do it,
다른 분들은 못하실 수도 있지만,
but maybe you can.
하지만 어쩌면 그럴 수도 있습니다.
Persuasion is about striking a chord with them.
설득은 그들과 화음을 치는 것에 대해.
And I think that's your forte
내 생각엔 그게 네 장점인 것 같아
when compared with other doctors.
다른 의사들과 비교했을 때
How would you know?
어떻게 알 수 있나요?
Find out for yourself
스스로 알아보세요
by talking to them.
그들과 이야기함으로써.
DREAM VILLAGE ANGEL HAVEN
드림 빌리지 엔젤 헤이븐
Here it is.
여기 있습니다.
CHILDREN'S PERSONAL INFORMATION CARD NAME: KIM U-HYEON
어린이 개인 정보 카드 이름: 김우현
SMALLER THAN OTHERS HIS AGE, BUT NOT SHORT
그 또래의 남들보다 작은, 하지만 짧지는 않아요
Was I abandoned?
내가 버려졌나요?
No one knows the answer to that question.
그 질문에 대한 답을 아는 사람은 아무도 없습니다.
But I hope that's not the case.
그러나 나는 그것이 사실이 아니기를 바랍니다.
That's why we record these
그렇기 때문에 우리는 이것을 녹음합니다.
as "found," not "abandoned."
'버려진 것'이 아니라 '발견된 것'으로요.
"Found."
"설립하다."
Right.
오른쪽.
Have you registered your DNA at the police station?
DNA를 등록하셨나요? 경찰서에서?
Your wife must be close
당신의 아내가 가까이 있어야합니다
to the new chief of the Hepatobiliary and Pancreas Department?
신임 간담도과장에게 그리고 췌장과?
He's the doctor who carried out her liver transplant.
그 사람이 의사예요 간 이식을 집도한 사람.
I see.
알겠어요.
But how did you know they were close?
그런데 그들이 가까이 있다는 것을 어떻게 알았나요?
They were eating together at the cafeteria.
그들은 함께 식사를 하고 있었어요 카페테리아에서.
Everyone is talking
다들 얘기하고 있어
about how he's rich, handsome, and single.
그 사람이 얼마나 부자이고, 잘생겼고, 독신인지에 대해서요.
Do women seriously think that he's handsome?
여자들은 진지하게 생각할까? 그 사람 잘생겼다고?
Are you joking?
농담하는 거야?
Objectively, he's far from ugly.
객관적으로 보면 그는 못생긴 사람과는 거리가 멀다.
You'll have to add a penalty stroke.
페널티 스트로크를 추가해야 합니다.
Is this cracked? Why are things so off recently?
이거 깨졌나요? 최근 상황이 왜 이렇게 안 좋은 걸까요?
What are you up to?
무슨 일을 하고 있나요?
There's nothing much to see.
별로 볼 것이 없습니다.
Let's eat.
먹자.
Okay.
좋아요.
Enjoy.
즐기다.
I can't guarantee the taste.
맛은 보장 못해요.
Don't worry. It's good.
괜찮아요. 좋다.
Lucky you. You get to eat her food every day.
행운을 빌어요. 당신은 매일 그녀의 음식을 먹게 됩니다.
That's not true. She hasn't cooked for me in ages.
그것은 사실이 아닙니다. 그녀는 오랫동안 나를 위해 요리를 해 주지 않았습니다.
She's so busy nowadays.
그녀는 요즘 너무 바빠요.
Right.
오른쪽.
Mom, her mom is a doctor too.
엄마, 그 사람 엄마도 의사예요.
Really? Which department?
정말? 어느 부서?
Family Medicine.
가정의학.
Goodness. No way.
선량. 안 돼요.
That's so fascinating.
정말 매력적이네요.
I'm currently being trained in that department too.
나는 지금 훈련을 받고 있어요. 그 부서에서도요.
So tell me. Where does she work?
그러니 말해 보세요. 그녀는 어디에서 일하나요?
Did she open her own practice?
그녀가 자신의 진료소를 열었나요?
Mom.
엄마.
Enough with the interrogation.
심문은 이제 그만.
Where's Dad?
아빠는 어디 계시나요?
Indoor golfing.
실내골프.
I hear indoor golf centers are the hottest place for affairs.
실내 골프장이 있다고 들었는데 일이 가장 핫한 곳.
Hey, what are you talking about?
무슨 소리 하는 거야?
Just eat.
그냥 먹어.
This is so good.
정말 좋아요.
I'm glad. Eat up.
기쁘다. 먹어라.
Eat up.
먹어라.
Okay.
좋아요.
DO NOT LET GO OF THE CATHETER UNTIL THE PROCEDURE IS DONE
카테터를 놓지 마십시오 절차가 완료될 때까지
Thank you for the meal.
식사해주셔서 감사합니다.
-Thank you for the meal. -Okay. You can go upstairs.
-식사해주셔서 감사합니다. -좋아요. 위층으로 갈 수 있습니다.
JUNG-MIN'S DAD
정민 아빠
Let's go.
가자.
Where are you going? Go up.
어디 가세요? 올라가세요.
Hello, sir. Are you off today?
안녕하세요, 선생님. 오늘 쉬세요?
-The surgery was canceled. -I see.
-수술이 취소되었습니다. -알겠어요.
Why would they come all the way here to golf?
그들은 왜 오겠는가? 골프까지 여기까지 왔나요?
We're here, aren't we?
우리 여기 있잖아, 그렇지?
How long must we do this in hiding?
우리는 언제까지 숨어서 이 일을 해야 합니까?
I'm sick and tired of this.
나는 이것에 지쳤습니다.
Wait…
잠깐…
A bracelet?
팔찌?
AVICHEN 24K DIAMOND BRACELET
아비첸 24K 다이아몬드 팔찌
And it was 5,820,000 won?
그리고 5,820,000원이었나?
This is a designer brand.
디자이너 브랜드 입니다.
-Mother. -Yes?
-어머니. -예?
Did you recently purchase a bracelet?
최근에 팔찌를 구입하셨나요?
Gosh, no.
이런, 아니.
I didn't.
나는하지 않았다.
I see.
알겠어요.
AVICHEN 24K DIAMOND BRACELET
아비첸 24K 다이아몬드 팔찌
It's pretty.
예쁘네요.
But why did he buy this?
그런데 그 사람은 왜 이걸 샀어요?
-Did you just come home? -Yes.
- 방금 집에 오셨나요? -예.
How was golf?
골프는 어땠나요?
It was so-so.
그저 그랬다.
Honey,
여보,
did you buy a bracelet?
팔찌 샀어?
A bracelet?
팔찌?
Why are you so surprised?
왜 그렇게 놀랐나요?
I found this in your pocket.
네 주머니에서 이걸 찾았어.
It was pretty expensive. Why did you buy it?
꽤 비쌌어요. 왜 샀어요?
It's strange…
이상하다…
how you're not answering me.
당신이 어떻게 나에게 대답하지 않는거야.
Why would you look inside my pockets?
왜 내 주머니 안을 들여다보려는 거야?
I checked them before taking the clothes to the dry cleaners.
옷을 가져가기 전에 확인했어요 세탁소에.
You really are a buzzkill, you know that?
당신은 정말 버즈킬이에요, 그거 알아요?
It's your birthday soon.
곧 당신의 생일입니다.
My birthday?
내 생일?
It'll be in two months.
두달 후면 됩니다.
I was going to brag about getting your gift early.
자랑하려고 했는데 선물을 일찍 받는 것에 대해.
Gosh, you ruined everything.
맙소사, 당신이 모든 걸 망쳤어요.
Seriously?
진지하게?
Then did you think it was for me?
그럼 그게 날 위한 거라고 생각했어?
Well…
음…
You've never bought me such things.
당신은 나에게 그런 것을 사준 적이 없습니다.
I know you like luxury items.
당신이 명품을 좋아하는 것으로 알고 있어요.
Did you forget how much you spent recently at the department store?
최근에 지출한 금액을 잊으셨나요? 백화점에서?
It was just that one time.
딱 한 번이었어요.
If that's the case,
그렇다면,
where is it?
어디야?
Since I found out about it anyway, can I just have it now?
어쨌든 그 사실을 알게 된 이후로, 지금 그냥 가져도 될까요?
No!
아니요!
It's in my office.
내 사무실에 있어요.
Really?
정말?
I wanted to see it right now. What a shame.
당장 보고 싶었어요. 정말 부끄러운 일입니다.
Honey.
꿀.
You must be exhausted after golfing, right?
넌 지쳤나봐 골프를 치고 난 후죠?
Yes, I need to rest.
응, 쉬어야 해.
-Really? -Yes.
-정말? -예.
Should I massage your shoulders?
어깨 마사지할까?
They're so stiff.
너무 뻣뻣해요.
That feels good.
기분 좋아요.
This part.
이 부분.
It's okay. I just need to rest.
괜찮아요. 난 그냥 쉬어야 해.
Shall I fill the bathtub?
욕조를 채워드릴까요?
I'd love that.
나는 그것을 좋아할 것이다.
Okay. Come out in ten minutes.
좋아요. 10분 뒤에 나오세요.
Okay.
좋아요.
Can I come in?
들어갈 수 있나요?
You're already in.
당신은 이미 들어와 있습니다.
It's been a while since you had wine in the bathtub, right?
오랜만에 와인을 마셨다. 욕조에 있는 거 맞지?
What's gotten into you with all this treatment?
당신에게 무엇이 들어왔나요? 이 모든 치료로?
That's the power of gifts.
That's the power of gifts.
Drink slowly.
천천히 마셔보세요.
Do you think…
당신은 생각합니까?
it's that easy for someone to change?
사람이 변하는 게 그렇게 쉽나요?
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
You see,
알다시피,
I'm a dedicated mother and wife to the bone.
나는 헌신적인 엄마예요 그리고 아내는 뼈속까지.
You know me.
당신은 나를 알고 있습니다.
I'm the icon of selflessness and devotion.
나는 이타심과 헌신의 아이콘이다.
Right.
오른쪽.
I know I've changed due to certain situations.
나도 내가 변했다는 걸 알아 특정 상황으로 인해.
But my family is my top priority.
하지만 내 가족이 최우선입니다.
That'll never change.
그건 절대 변하지 않을 거예요.
Honey.
꿀.
Why didn't you tell me about Seung-hi?
왜 승희에 대해 말하지 않았나요?
I knew you'd ask.
나는 당신이 물어볼 줄 알았습니다.
It's nothing good, so I didn't bother to tell you.
별거 아닌데, 그래서 굳이 너한테 말하지 않았어.
Have you spoken with her?
그녀와 얘기해 보셨나요?
We've just greeted each other.
우리는 방금 서로 인사를 했습니다.
Is she married?
그 사람 결혼했어요?
Beats me.
나를 이겼다.
Do you think she still hates me?
그 사람이 아직도 나를 미워한다고 생각하시나요?
I doubt she loves you.
그녀가 당신을 사랑하는지 의심스럽습니다.
She's still as beautiful as she was then.
그녀는 그때나 지금이나 여전히 아름답습니다.
She looks so elegant that she'd turn heads.
그녀는 정말 우아해 보여요 그녀가 머리를 돌릴 것이라고.
It feels like I'm the only one who has aged.
그것은 다음과 같은 느낌이다 나이가 많은 사람은 나뿐이다.
You don't look too bad either.
당신도 별로 나빠 보이지는 않네요.
Really?
정말?
Sure.
확신하는.
You're right.
당신 말이 맞아요.
I still got the body.
나는 아직도 시체를 갖고 있다.
Don't stay in there for too long.
거기에 너무 오래 머물지 마세요.
Okay.
좋아요.
Do you not like it, sir?
마음에 안드시나요 선생님?
Would you like to see something else?
다른 것을 보고 싶나요?
It's okay.
괜찮아요.
I'll take it.
내가 가져갈게.
How would you like to pay?
어떻게 지불하시겠습니까?
Twelve-month installments, please.
12개월 할부로 부탁드립니다.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
What brings you here?
무슨 일로 여기까지 왔나요?
I came to talk to you about a personal matter.
나는 당신과 이야기하러 왔습니다 개인적인 문제에 대해서.
So let me speak casually to you for a moment.
그럼 아무렇지도 않게 얘기해볼까 잠시 동안 당신에게.
What do you want?
당신은 무엇을 원하세요?
I don't know…
모르겠어요…
how to begin.
시작하는 방법.
To be honest,
솔직히 말하자면,
I don't think
나는 생각하지 않는다
I've ever apologized to you.
나는 당신에게 사과한 적이 있습니다.
I know it happened ages ago,
나는 그 일이 오래 전에 일어났다는 것을 안다.
so bringing it up now…
그래서 지금 꺼내는 중...
may feel odd.
이상하게 느껴질 수도 있습니다.
But still,
하지만 여전히,
I'd like to apologize.
사과드리고 싶습니다.
I won't justify my actions and say I was immature back then.
나는 내 행동을 정당화하지 않을 것이다 그땐 내가 철없었다고.
I…
나는…
hurt you
당신에게 상처를 주다
very deeply.
아주 깊이.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
I'm truly sorry.
정말 죄송해요.
I mean it.
진심이에요.
I wanted to ask you for forgiveness back then.
나는 당신에게 묻고 싶었습니다. 그때 용서를 구합니다.
But I was a coward.
하지만 나는 겁쟁이였습니다.
To be honest,
솔직히 말해서,
you were so amazing and successful in my eyes
넌 정말 대단했어 내 눈에는 성공했어
that I thought you'd just brush it off.
난 당신이 그냥 털어버릴 거라고 생각했어요.
That was thoughtless of me.
그건 나에 대해 경솔한 생각이었다.
How could you have forgiven me?
어떻게 나를 용서할 수 있었나요?
I'm sure…
나는 확신한다…
you've had
당신은 가지고 있었다
your share of painful moments.
고통스러운 순간의 당신의 몫.
I don't even know how to respond to this.
나는 이것에 어떻게 대응해야할지조차 모릅니다.
That was ages ago.
오래 전 일이었습니다.
I moved on.
나는 계속 나아갔다.
There's no need to feel guilty.
죄책감을 느낄 필요가 없습니다.
If apologizing made you feel better, I'm glad.
사과를 했다면 기분이 좋아지셨다니 다행이네요.
Really?
정말?
I'm relieved.
나는 안심했다.
How have you been?
잘 지내셨나요?
Are you married?
결혼하셨나요?
It's a bit absurd to hear you trying to be friendly and ask questions.
듣기엔 좀 황당한데 친절하게 대하고 질문하려고 노력합니다.
Just because I don't make an issue out of our past
내가하지 않기 때문에 우리의 과거를 문제 삼아
doesn't mean we can be friends.
그렇다고 우리가 친구가 될 수 있다는 뜻은 아니다.
CHOI SEUNG-HI
최승희
EMERGENCY MEDICAL CENTER
응급 의료 센터
-Did you page me? -Yes.
- 나한테 전화했어? -예.
It's about Mr. Oh Chang-gyu, our VIP.
우리 VIP 오창규씨 이야기입니다.
He got discharged and was about to get in his car
그는 퇴원했어요 그리고 그의 차에 타려고 했어
when he suddenly collapsed.
갑자기 쓰러졌을 때.
-He's here in the ER. -What?
-그는 여기 응급실에 있어요. -무엇?
They're carrying out CPR in the ICU.
중환자실에서 심폐소생술(CPR)을 실시하고 있습니다.
-Administer 1ml of epinephrine. -Yes, ma'am.
-에피네프린 1ml를 투여한다. -네, 부인.
Chairman Oh.
오 회장.
What are you doing? Prepare the defibrillator.
뭐하세요? 제세동기를 준비합니다.
Yes, ma'am.
네, 부인.
Let me check his readings.
그가 읽은 내용을 확인해 보겠습니다.
I'm seeing V-fib. Let's shock him now.
V-fib가 보입니다. 이제 그에게 충격을 주자.
Charge it to 150J.
150J까지 충전하세요.
150J, charged.
150J, 충전됨.
Stand clear.
분명히 서십시오.
One, two, administering shock.
하나, 둘, 충격을 가하는 거죠.
Once more. 150J.
다시 한 번. 150J.
I charged it to 150J.
150J까지 충전했어요.
Stand clear. One, two, administering shock.
분명히 서십시오. 하나, 둘, 충격을 가하는 거죠.
Administer 300ml of amiodarone.
아미오다론 300ml를 투여한다.
-Yes, ma'am. -Charge it to 200J.
-네, 부인. -200J까지 충전하세요.
One, two, administering shock.
하나, 둘, 충격을 가하는 거죠.
-Did you administer the amiodarone? -Yes, I did.
-아미오다론은 투여하셨나요? -네, 그랬어요.
No.
아니요.
Charge it to 200J.
200J까지 충전하세요.
-I'll take over. -Okay.
-내가 맡겠습니다. -좋아요.
I charged it to 200J.
200J까지 충전했어요.
Move. One…
이동하다. 하나…
Two…
두…
Administering shock.
쇼크 관리.
Dr. Cha.
차 박사.
Dr. Cha!
차 박사님!
Open your eyes!
눈을 뜨세요!
DOCTOR CHA
차 박사
Does that lady have some kind of irresistible charm I don't know about?
저 여자는 뭔가를 가지고 있나요? 내가 모르는 거부할 수 없는 매력이 있는 걸까?
Why do men swarm around her?
왜 남자들은 그녀 주위에 모여들까?
You didn't hear?
못 들었어?
They say Dr. Cha and GS Professor Seo are seeing each other.
차 박사님과 GS 서교수님이라고 하더군요 서로 만나고 있어요.
Honestly, this is driving me crazy too!
솔직히 이것도 나를 미치게 만든다!
Ms. Jang Hae-nam disappeared.
장해남씨가 사라졌다.
Are you out of your mind?
정신이 나갔나요?
How dare an incompetent resident like you humiliate our hospital?
감히 무능한 주민이 당신이 우리 병원을 모욕하는 것처럼요?
Do you think you can continue to work?
계속 일할 수 있을 것 같나요?
I'm afraid I'll have to quit working at the hospital.
안타깝지만 그만둬야 할 것 같습니다. 병원에서 일해요.